以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以他慷慨地同意今天来
so he graciously agreed to come today
等一切准备就绪，然后在
and so everything is ready then and in
你的截止就像是155啊
your cutoff is like 155 yeah
为什么会这样
why is there
你知道有人改变了分辨率
you know somebody changed the resolution
看来不过这没什么不不
it seems but that's fine doesn't doesn't
打扰我们，所以我要告诉你
bother us so I'm gonna tell you about
让我们说最古老的一个
let's say one of the most ancient
优化方法比简单方法简单得多
optimization methods much simpler than
实际上你是更先进的方法
in fact the more advanced methods you
已经在课堂上见过
have already seen in class and
有趣的是这种更古老的方法
interestingly this more ancient method
仍然是培训的方法
remains the method for training
大型机器学习系统和
large-scale machine learning systems and
所以有历史的点点
so there's a little bit of history
我不会去太多
around that I'm not gonna go too much
走进了历史，但底线
into the history but the bottom line
可能吉尔也提到了
which probably Gil has also mentioned to
你在课堂上，至少是大的
you in class that at least for large
数据科学问题到底是什么
data science problems in the end stuff
减少解决优化问题
reduces to solving an optimization
问题和当前时间这些
problem and in current times these
优化问题非常大
optimization problems are pretty large
所以人们真的开始喜欢的东西
so people actually started liking stuff
像发明的梯度下降
like gradient descent which was invented
由Cauchy回来当天，这是
by Cauchy back in the day and this is
我是如何写出抽象问题的
how I'm writing the abstract problem and
我想看到的是否合适
what I wanna see is okay is it fitting
在页面上这是我的实现
on the page this is my implementation in
梯度下降的MATLAB只是设置
MATLAB of gradient descent just to set
你知道这个东西的阶段
the stage that you know this stuff
看起来真的很简单你已经看过了
really looks simple you've already seen
梯度下降，今天基本上
gradient descent and today essentially
简而言之，真正发生了什么变化
in a nutshell what really changes in
这种梯度下降的实现
this implementation of gradient descent
今天就是这个部分
today is this part that's it
所以你看过梯度下降我只是
so you've seen gradient descent I'm only
要改变这一行和
going to change this one line and the
令人惊讶的是，改变那一行
change of that one line surprisingly is
让你知道所有的深度学习
driving you know all the deep learning
工具箱和所有大型机器
toolboxes and all of large scale machine
学习等这是一个
learning etc this is an
过度简化但道德上就是这样
oversimplification but morally that's it
让我们来看看发生了什么，所以我
so let's look at what's happening so I
很快就会变得非常具体
will become very concrete pretty soon
但抽象地说，我希望你看
but abstractly what I want you to look
在是
at is the
我们遇到的各种优化问题
kinds of optimization problems we are
在机器学习中解决，我会
solving in machine learning and I'll
给你非常具体的例子
give you very concrete examples of these
优化问题让你可以
optimization problems so that you can
更好地与他们联系，但我只是
relate to them better but I'm just
把它写成所有的关键主题
writing this as the key topic that all
我要去的优化问题
the optimization problems that I'm going
今天谈谈他们看起来像那样
to talk about today they look like that
我们试图在成本上找到一个x
we're trying to find an x over a cost
功能可以是成本函数
function where the cost function can be
在现代机器中写成一笔钱
written as a sum in modern day machine
学习说法这些也被称为
learning parlance these are also called
遇到的有限和问题
finite sum problems in case you run into
这个词和这个叫有限
that term and this is called finite
因为n在这里纯有限
because n is finite here in pure
优化理论说法n可以
optimization Theory parlance n can
实际上去无限，然后他们
actually go to infinity and then they
被称为随机优化
are called stochastic optimization
只有术语的问题，如果有的话
problems just for terminology if while
在互联网上搜索你遇到了一些
searching the internet you run into some
这样的术语让你有点了解
such terminology so you kind of know
它意味着什么所以这里是我们的设置
what it means so here is our set up in
机器学习我们有一堆
machine learning we have a bunch of
我在这张幻灯片上训练数据好了
training data ok on this slide I am
调用x1到xn这些是
calling x1 through xn these are the
稍后训练数据原始功能
training data the raw features later
实际上我停止为他们写X.
actually I stopped writing X for them
并用字母A写出来但是
and write them with the letter A but
希望没关系，所以x1到xn
hopefully that's okay so x1 through xn
这些可能只是原始图像
these could be just raw images for
imagenet中的实例或其他图像
instance in imagenet or some other image
数据集可能有文本文件
data set there could be text documents
它们可以是y1到yn中的任何东西
they could be anything y1 through yn in
经典机器学习想到它们
classical machine learning think of them
加上减1标签猫不是猫或在
as plus minus 1 labels cat not cat or in
回归设置为一些实数
a regression setup as some real number
所以我们有D的训练数据
so that's a training data we have D
尺寸原始矢量和那些和
dimensional raw vectors and of those and
我们有相应的标签可以
we have corresponding labels which can
要么是加1减1
be either plus minus 1 in a
分类设置或实数
classification setting or a real number
在回归设置中它是那种
in a regression setting it's kind of
对我现在的讲座来说并不重要
immaterial for my lecture right now so
这是输入和任何人
that's the input and whenever anybody
说大型机器学习什么
says large-scale machine learning what
我们真的是说
do we really mean
我们的意思是，无论是N和d可
what we mean is that both N and D can be
大，那么这意味着什么
large so what does that mean in words
有n是训练数据的数量
there n is the number of training data
点，因此n可能是这些天什么
points so n could be these days what
百万千万
million ten million hundred million
取决于计算机和数据有多大
depends on how big computers and data
你得到的东西，所以n可以是巨大的
sets you got so n can be huge d the
维度我们的向量
dimensionality the vectors that we are
与原工作的载体，可以
working with the raw vectors that can
如果X是一个也很大
also be pretty large think if X is an
图像，如果它是一个百万像素的图像哇
image if it's a megapixel image wow
如果你是的话，这些就像一百万
these like a million already if you are
有人喜欢kritio或Facebook或者
somebody like kriti o or Facebook or
谷歌和你在网上服务
Google and you're serving web
广告d这些都是特征
advertisements D these are the features
也能像在连7亿
could be like in 700 million even a
他们编码各种各样的十亿
billion where they encode all sorts of
他们收集的令人讨厌的东西和信息
nasty stuff and information they collect
关于你作为用户如此多的讨厌
about you as users so so many nasty
他们可以收集的东西，所以DNN是
things they can collect right so DNN are
巨大的，因为D和n都是
huge and it's because both D and n are
我们有兴趣思考
huge we are interested in thinking of
大规模的优化方法
optimization methods for large-scale
机器学习，可以处理这样的
machine learning that can handle such
大DNL和这推动了很多
big dnl and this is driving a lot of
研究也在理论计算机上
research also in theoretical computer
科学包括搜索子
science including the search for sub
各种线性时间算法
linear time algorithms in all sorts of
哈希技巧中的数据结构就是这样
data structures in hashing tricks just
对付这两个量等等
to deal with these two quantities so
这是一个示例超级玩具示例和
here is an example super toy example and
我希望你知道我能做到的
I hope really you know by that I can
稍后挤一点证明
squeeze in a little bit of a proof later
在接近年底我会在这里进行表决
on towards the end I'll take a vote here
在课堂上看看你是否感兴趣
in class to see if you are interested
让我们来看看最经典的问题
let's look at the most classic question
最小二乘回归是一个矩阵
least squares regression is a matrix of
观察或抱歉测量B是
observations or sorry measurements B are
你想要解决的观察结果
the observations you're trying to solve
斧头减去B整个正方形
ax minus B whole square
当然是一个线性方程组
of course a linear system of equations
线性的最经典问题
the most classical problem in linear
代数也可以这样写
algebra can also be written like that
让我们说这可以有希望地扩大
let's say this can be expanded hopefully
你对这个规范很满意
you are comfortable with this norm right
所以x2square只是定义为
so x2 square this is just defined as
这就是那种符号的定义
that's the definition of that notation
但是我现在只写一次
but I'll just write it only once now I
希望大家充分了解，如此
hope you are fully familiar with that so
通过扩展我设法写
by expanding that I managed to write
就我而言，最小二乘问题
least squares problem in terms of what I
把有限和称为正确，这就是它
call the finite sum right so it's just
在他们的结尾遍历所有行
going over all the rows in a their end
让我们这么说，这是最少的
rows let's say so that's the least
正方形经典最小二乘问题
squares classical least squares problem
它假定我们这个有限的总和形式
it assumes this finite sum form that we
关心另一个随机的例子
care about another random example
所谓的拉，所以也许你有
something called la so maybe you have if
你们中的任何人都玩过机器
anybody of you has played with machine
你可以学习统计工具包
learning statistics toolkits you may
见过laSollaSol
have seen something called la Sol la Sol
基本上是最小二乘，但有
is essentially least squares but there's
在结束另一个简单的术语，
another simple term at the end that
再次看起来像我支持向量的F.
again looks like F of I support vector
机器曾经超过他们的马
machines once over horse of they're
还是人一个主力马谁
still a workhorse horse of people who
处理中小型数据
work with small to medium sized data
深度学习需要大量资金
deep learning stuff requires huge amount
如果您有中小型数据
of data if you have small to medium
数据逻辑回归量
amount of data logistic regression
支持向量机等树木这
support vector machines trees etc this
将是第一个去他们的方法
will be a first go to methods they still
这些问题非常广泛使用
very widely used these problems are
再次以损失的方式写下来
again written in terms of a loss over
训练数据所以这又有了这个
training data so this again has this
很棒的格式，我现在才会
awesome format which I'll just now
记录在这里我甚至可能不需要
record here I may not even need to
有时我会用它来写它
repeat it sometimes I write it with a
你可能会想到一些正常化
normalization you may wonder at some
指出为什么那个有限和问题和
point why as that finite sum problem and
也许你想要它的例子
maybe the example that you want it to
看到的是类似的东西如此之深
see is something like that so deep
神经网络非常受欢迎
neural networks that are very popular
这些天他们又是另一个
these days they are just yet another
这个有限和问题的例子如何
example of this finite sum problem how
他们是你的一个例子吗？
are they an example of that so you have
n训练数据点有神经
n training data points there's a neural
网络丢失就像交叉熵或什么
network loss like cross-entropy or what
你有没有把损失交叉到任何一个
have you squared loss cross into any
有点失落为什么眼睛是标签猫
kind of loss why eyes are the labels cat
不是猫或其他什么或他们可能是她
not cat or whatever or they may be her
多班
multi class
然后你有一个传递函数
and then you have a transfer function
称为深度神经网络
called a deep neural network which takes
原始图像作为输入并生成一个
raw images as input and generates a
预测这是否是狗或不
prediction whether this is a dog or not
整件事我只是叫DNn
that whole thing I'm just calling DN n
所以这是一个眼睛的功能
so it's a function of a eyes which are
训练数据X的重量
the training data X are the weight
我是神经网络的矩阵
matrices of the neural network so I'm
只是压缩了整个神经网络
just compressed the whole neural network
进入这种表示法
into this notation
再一次，它只不过是一个例子
once again it's nothing but an instance
有限的总和使FI在那里
of that finite sum so that F I in there
捕获整个神经网络
captures the entire neural network
建筑，但在数学上它是
architecture but mathematically it's
仍然只是一个特定的例子
still just one particular instance of
这个有限的总和问题和人
this finite sum problem and in people
谁做了很多统计数据最多
who do lot of statistics maximum
可能性估计这是对数
likelihood estimation this is log
我们想要的n次观察的可能性
likelihood over n observations we want
最大化对数可能性
to maximize log likelihood once again
这只是一个有限的总和
just a finite sum so pretty much most of
我们感兴趣的问题
the problems that we are interested in
机器学习和统计时我
machine learning and statistics when I
写下来把它们写成一个
write them write them down as an
优化问题他们看起来像这样
optimization problem they look like this
有限和问题，那是
finite sum problems and that's the
发展专业的原因
reason to develop specialized
这样的优化程序来解决
optimization procedures to solve such
有限和问题，这就是SGD
finite sum problems and that's where SGD
进来好了，所以这是一种只
comes in ok so that's kind of just the
让我们来看看如何去
backdrop let's look at now how to go
关于解决这些问题
about solving these problems
所以希望这个迭代很熟悉
so hopefully this iteration is familiar
你渐渐下降就好了
to you gradient descent right ok so just
对于X的符号f指的是那个
for notation f of X refers to that
X的整个总和FsubI指的是
entire summation F sub I of X refers to
一个单一的组件好吧，如果你这样做
a single component ok so if you were to
试着解决这个问题是为了尽量减少这一点
try to solve that is to minimize this
成本函数神经网络SVM
cost function neural network SVM
什么是你使用梯度下降
what-have-you using gradient descent
这就是一次迭代的样子
that's what one iteration would look
喜欢因为它是一个有限的和梯度
like because it's a finite sum gradients
是线性运算符
are linear operators
你知道总和的梯度就是总和
you know gradient of the sum is the sum
梯度的渐变使得渐变
of the gradients so that's gradient
你的血统，现在我只想问一个
descent for you and now I'll just ask a
修辞问题，如果你把
rhetoric question that if you put
自己在你的鞋子知道
yourself in the shoes of you know
算法设计师你有些事情
algorithm designers some things that you
可能想要考虑一下你可能没有的东西
may want to think about what may you not
就像这个迭代一样大
like about this iteration given that big
我告诉过你的BigD故事
and Big D story that I told you so
任何人都有任何保留或约
anybody have any reservations or about
这次迭代的缺点是任何评论
drawbacks of this iteration any comments
这是一笔相当大的收入
it's a pretty big sum especially
什么是一个很大的缺点和
anything that is a big drawback and
这是最主要的缺点
there is that is the prime drawback for
大规模的n可以是巨大的
large scale that n can be huge there can
一些其他的缺点
be variety of other drawbacks some of
这些你以前可能见过，如果
those you may have seen previously if
当人们比较是否这样做
when people compare whether to do
渐变或做牛顿等但是
gradient or to do Newton etc but for
今天的目的是有限总和的大
purpose of today for finite sums the big
缺点是在a处计算梯度
drawback is computing gradient at a
单点这是下标XK
single point this is a subscript XK
错过那里涉及计算
missing there involves computing the
和的总和的梯度
gradient of that entire sum that sum is
巨大，所以要做一个渐变
huge so getting a single gradient to do
的梯度下降为单一步骤
a single step of gradient descent for a
大数据集可能需要几个小时或
large data set could take you hours or
天，这是一个主要的缺点，但随后
days so that's a major drawback but then
好的，如果你发现了这个缺点
okay if you identify that drawback
任何人都有任何想法如何反击
anybody have any ideas how to counter
这个缺点至少可以说纯粹来自
that drawback at least say purely from
我听说过工程学的观点
an engineering perspective I heard
某物
something
使用LexA和一批mash灯来
using LexA and a batch of mash lights to
保卫我们，也许别人有
defend us and maybe somebody else has
任何人都想要的基本相同的想法
essentially the same idea anybody wants
建议如何规避那么大
to suggest how to circumvent that big
在那里结束什么东西假设你
end stuff in there anything suppose you
可以在这实现你会做什么
can implement in this what would you do
完全n的andum样本所以这些是
andum sample of the full n so these are
所有优秀的想法，因此你们大家
all excellent ideas and hence you folks
在课堂上发现了最多
in the class have discovered the most
优化机器的重要方法
important method for optimizing machine
学习问题坐在这里几个
learning problems sitting here in a few
时刻不是那么大，所以这一部分
moments isn't that great so the part
缺少的当然是要做的
that is missing is of course to make
这个想法的作用是什么呢？
sense of does this idea work why does it
工作所以这个想法真的是在心里
work so this idea is really at the heart
随机梯度下降所以让我们
of stochastic gradient descent so let's
看，我也许可以给你看一个例子
see I maybe I can show you an example
实际上，我会告诉你一个
actually that I I'll show you a
模拟我发现有人很好
simulation I found on somebody's nice
关于那个网页的确切的想法
web page about that so exactly your idea
只是放入一些轻微的数学符号
just put in slight mathematical notation
如果在每次迭代时我们都会这样做
that what if at each iteration we
随机选择一些整数IK.
randomly pick some integer I K out of
n个训练数据点和我们
the n training data points and and we
而只是正确执行此更新
instead just perform this update right
所以你的，而不是使用完整
so you instead of using the full
渐变你只需计算渐变
gradient you just compute the gradient
一个随机选择的数据点
of a single randomly chosen data point
那么你对那个做了什么呢？
so what have you done with that one
如果n，迭代现在快n倍
iteration is now n times faster if n
是一百万或十亿哇
were a million or a billion wow that's
超快，但为什么这应该工作
super fast but why should this work
对
right
我的意思是我可以做很多其他事情
I mean I could have done many other
我能做的事情我可以
things I could have constant I could
没有做任何更新，只是输出
have not done any update and just output
零矢量，即使是偶数
the zero vector that would take even
较短的时间，这也是一个想法意味着一个
lesser time that's also an idea means a
糟糕的想法，但这是一个类似的想法
bad idea but it's an idea in the similar
我可以做各种各样的联赛
league I could have done a variety of
其他的事情，你为什么会认为
other things why would you think that
只是你知道替换一些
just you know replacing that some with
只有一个随机的例子可以让我们工作
just one random example may work let's
查看更多有关那么一点点的
see a little bit more about that so of
当然它快了n倍，关键
course it's n times faster and the key
现在问我们这里的问题
question for us here right now the
科学问题是这样做的
scientific question is does this make
感觉它具有很大的工程意义
sense it makes great engineering sense
它是算法还是数学
does it make algorithmic or mathematical
感让这个想法在做的东西的
sense so this idea of doing stuff in the
实际上是随机的
stochastic manner was actually
最初由罗宾斯在Monro提出
originally proposed by Robbins in Monro
在某个地方，我想在1951年左右，那就是
somewhere I think around 1951 and that's
我们最先进的方法
the most advanced method that we are
基本上使用目前所以我将展示
essentially using currently so I'll show
你这个想法有意义但也许
you that this idea makes sense but maybe
让我们先看一下比较
let's first just look at a comparison of
SGD在这个梯度下降
SGD with gradient descent in this
仿真所以这就是MATLAB代码
simulation so this is that MATLAB code
梯度下降，这只是一个
of gradient descent and this is just a
模拟梯度下降就像你一样
simulation of gradient descent as you
选择一个不同的步长，即伽玛
pick a different step size that gamma in
在那里你走向最佳的if
there you move towards the optimum if
步长你小很多
the step size is small you make many
小步骤进展，你到达那里
small steps progress and you reach there
这是一个有条件的问题
that's for a well-conditioned problem in
它会带来一个病态的问题
an ill-conditioned problem it takes you
在神经网络类型中甚至更大
even larger in a neural network type
你需要非凸的问题
problem which is non convex you have to
通常使用较小的步长
typically work with smaller step sizes
如果你采取更大的，你可以得到
and if you take bigger ones you can get
疯狂的振荡，但那是渐变
crazy oscillations but that's gradient
比较下降让我们希望如此
descent in comparison let's hope that
这种加载正确，甚至有一个
this loads correctly well there's even a
罗宾斯的核心图片
picture of Robbins who's a core
随机梯度的发现者
discoverer of the stochastic gradient
方法有一个很好的模拟
method there's a nice simulation that
而不是我
instead of me
国王那种确定性的血统
King that kind of deterministic descent
在调用所有梯度下降之后
after all gradient descent is called
在每一个步骤中，梯度下降
gradient descent at every step it
下降它降低了成本函数
descends it decreases the cost function
实际上是随机梯度下降
stochastic gradient descent is actually
在每一步都没有用的用词不当
a misnomer at every step it doesn't do
任何下降它不会减少
any descent it does not decrease the
成本函数，所以你可以看到每一个
cost function so you can see at every
那些是成本的轮廓
step those are the contours of the cost
功能有时它有时会上升
function sometimes it goes up sometimes
它下降它波动，但它
it goes down it fluctuates around but it
一种随机似乎仍是
kind of stochastically still seems to be
在最佳和最佳方面取得进展
making progress towards the optimum and
随机梯度下降，因为它
stochastic gradient descent because it's
不使用精确的渐变只是工作
not using exact gradients just working
实际上，这些随机的例子
with these random examples it actually
对步长更敏感
is much more sensitive to step sizes and
你可以看到我增加步长
you can see as I increase the step size
它的行为就像实际上一样
its behavior this is like actually full
模拟玩具问题所以
simulation for a toy problem so
最初所以我希望你注意到
initially so what I want you to notice
让我通过这个，你知道一些
is let me go through this you know a few
时代一直在看你的模式
times keep looking at what patterns you
可能会注意到这条线是怎么回事
may notice in how that line is
希望这足够大
fluctuating hopefully this is big enough
对于每个人都可以看到这样的滑块
for everybody to see okay so this slider
我正在转移只是步长
that I'm shifting is just the step size
所以，让我在你遇到的情况下提醒你
so let me just remind you in case you
忘记了我们正在运行XK的迭代
forgot the iteration we are running XK
加1是XK减去一些好吧没关系
plus 1 is XK minus some it okay okay
它被称为alpha有时候有些
it's called alpha there times some
您计算的随机选择的数据点
randomly chosen data point you compute
它的渐变这是SGD，这就是我们
its gradient this is SGD that's what we
正在运行，我们扔掉了大量的
are running and we threw away tons of
我们没有充分使用的信息
information we didn't use the full
渐变我们只是使用这种原油
gradient we just using this crude crude
渐变所以这个过程非常好
gradient so this process is very
敏感的其他参数
sensitive to the other parameter in the
系统，这是步长大小更
system which is the step size much more
事实上，比梯度下降敏感
sensitive than gradient descent in fact
当我改变步骤时你会看到
and you let's see as I vary the step
大小看看你是否能注意到一些父母
size see if you can notice some parents
如何尝试走向最佳状态
on how it tries to go towards an optimum
也是这个的放大版本
is a zoomed in version also of this
稍后在这里，很快就会到来
later here and come to that shortly
我会再次重复，然后我会
again I'll repeat again and then I'll
如果你，请问你的意见
ask you for your observations if you
注意一些我不知道的模式
notice some patterns I don't know if
他们知道你一定很明显
they're necessarily apparent you know
这就是模式的原因，因为我
that's the thing with patterns because I
知道答案，所以我看到了模式
know the answer so I see the pattern if
你不知道你可能或可能的答案
you don't know the answer you may or may
没有看到模式，但我想看看是否
not see the pattern but I want to see if
你实际上看到我移动时的模式
you actually see the pattern as I move
改变步长，也许就是这样
change the step size so maybe that was
任何人都有足够的模拟
enough simulation anybody have any
评论你可能采用何种模式
comments on what kind of pattern you may
已观察到其他任何评论
have observed any other comments there's
还有一件有趣的事情发生了
one more interesting thing happening
这是一个非常非常典型的事情
here which is a very very typical thing
为SGD中的原因之一人
for SGD in one of the reasons why people
爱SGD让我再次这样做
love SGD let me do that once again
简单地说这是一个很小的步长
briefly okay this is tiny step size
接近零几乎为零并不完全正确
almost zero close to zero is not exactly
零，所以你看看会发生什么
zero so you see what happens for a very
它看起来很小
tiny step size it doesn't look that
随机权利，但那是一种
stochastic right but that's kind of
如果Takei是非常明显的话
obvious from there if a Takei is very
很小，你几乎不会采取任何行动
tiny you'll hardly make any move so
事实看起来非常稳定
things will look very stable and in fact
随机梯度的速度
the speed at which stochastic gradient
收敛这就是极其敏感的原因
converges that's why extremely sensitive
如何选择它仍然的步长
to how you pick the step size it's still
拿出一个开放的研究问题
an open research problem to come up with
选择步长的最佳方法还可以
the best way to pick step sizes okay so
虽然很简单，但事实并非如此
it's even though it's simple it doesn't
意味着它是微不足道的，因为我改变了步骤
mean it's trivial and as I vary the step
大小可以取得一些进展和它
size okay to make some progress and it
走向解决方案你知道吗？
goes towards the solution are you know
开始说它似乎是
beginning to say that it seems to be
在...中取得更稳定的进展
making a more stable progress in the
开始和接近时
beginning and when it comes close to the
解决方案它的波动更大而且
solution it's fluctuating more and the
步数越大，量越大
bigger the step size the amount of
解决方案附近的波动是Wilder
fluctuation near the solution is Wilder
因为他注意到那里只有一个
as he noticed back there but one
非常有趣的事情或多或少
very interesting thing is more or less
不断有更大的波动
constant there is more fluctuation also
在外面但你看到了
on the outside but you see that the
最初的部分似乎仍在制作中
initial part still seems to be making
非常好的进步和你来
pretty good progress and as you come
接近解决它更波动
close to the solution it fluctuates more
这是一个非常典型的典型
and that is a very principally typical
随机梯度下降的行为
behavior of stochastic gradient descent
在开始的时候，使快速
that in the beginning it makes rapid
大踏步走，这样你就可以看到你的训练
strides so you may see your training
损失减少哎呦超快，然后
loss decrease whoops super fast and then
有点你知道peterout就是这个
kind of you know peter out and it's this
让人们感到特别的行为
particular behavior which got people
超级兴奋，嘿机器
super excited that hey in machine
学习我们正在与各种各样的工作
learning we are working with all sorts
大数据我只想快速和
of big data I just want a quick and
在我的培训训练我脏进展
dirty progress on my training training I
不关心怎样以最好的
don't care about getting to the best
最佳，因为在机器学习你
optimum because in machine learning you
不要只关心解决
don't just care about solving the
你真正关心的优化问题
optimization problem you actually care
关于找到运作良好的解决方案
about finding solutions that work well
在看不见的数据上，这意味着你没有
on unseen data so that means you don't
想过度适应和解决
want to over fit and solve the
优化问题非常好
optimization problem supremely well so
快速初始化是很棒的
it's great to make rapid initial
进展以及如果在那之后进展
progress and if after that progress
彼得斯出来没关系
Peters out it's okay
这种直觉主义的陈述是
this intuitionistic statements that are
在一些很好的情况下制作像凸
making in some nice cases like convex
可以优化问题
optimization problems one can
数学完全量化这一块
mathematically fully quantify this one
可以证明定理量化它的东西
can prove theorems to quantify its thing
我说的有多接近
that I said in terms of how close how
速度快等特点，我们会看到一点点
fast and so on we'll see a little bit of
这就是真正发生的事情
that and this is what really happens to
SGD你知道它起初很好
SGD you know it makes great initial
进步，无论你如何使用
progress and regardless of how you use
步长接近最佳值
step sizes close to the optimum it can
无论是遇到问题或进入某种
either get stuck or enter some kind of
混乱的动态或只是表现得像疯了似的
chaos dynamics or just behave like crazy
所以这是典型的SGD，让我们看看
so that's typical of SGD and let's look
在没有任何轻微的数学洞察
at no slight mathematical insight into
大概为什么会发生这种行为
roughly why this behavior may happen
这是一个微不足道的一维
this is a trivial 1 dimensional
优化问题，但它传达了
optimization problem but it conveys the
显示此行为的原因
crux of why this behavior is displayed
通过随机梯度法得到它
by stochastic gradient methods that it
一开始工作得很好
works really well in the beginning
那么天知道会发生什么事
then it can God knows what happens when
它接近最佳状态
it comes close to the optimum anything
可能发生让我们在那看行不行如此
can happen so let's look at that okay so
让我们来看一个简单的一维
let's look at a simple one dimensional
优化问题我会画一些
optimization problem I'll kind of draw
它也许在另一边，这样
it out maybe on the other side so that
这方面的人不是
people on this side are not
处于不利地位，所以我只是抽出一个
disadvantaged so I'll just draw out a
最小二乘问题X是一个
least squares problem X is one
维先前我有人工智能
dimensional previously I had AI
转X现在AI也是如此标
transpose X now AI is also a scalar so
它只是1d所以一切都是1d所以
it's just 1d stuff everything is 1d so
这是我们将AI设想为X的设置
this is our set up think of AI into X
减去bi这些是二次函数
minus bi these are quadratic functions
对，所以他们看起来像这样
right so they look like this
对应不同的眼睛
corresponding to different eyes there's
喜欢坐在一些不同的功能
like some different functions sitting
等等，所以这些是我的不同
and so on so these are my n different
损失功能，我想尽量减少
loss functions and I want to minimize
那些我们知道我们实际上可以明确地
those we know we can actually explicitly
计算该问题的解决方案
compute the solution of that problem
对你设置，所以你设置衍生物
right you set so you set the derivative
将f的f设为0，以便设置渐变
of f of X to 0 so you set the gradient
对于X的0到0希望这很容易
of f of X to 0 hopefully that's easy for
如果你这样做，你会这样做
you to do so if you do that
分化将获得f的梯度
differentiation will get gradient of f
X可以很好地给出
of X will be just given by well you can
在你脑子里这样做我会写下来的
do that in your head I'll just write it
明确AIX减去bi时间AI
out explicitly AI X minus bi times AI is
等于0，你为X解决了这个问题
equal to 0 and you solve that for X you
让X星成为最小的最佳
get X star the optimum of this least
正方形问题，所以我们实际上
squares problem right so we actually
知道如何轻松解决它
know how to solve it pretty easily it's
实际上我得到了一个非常酷的例子
a really cool example actually I got
来自Dimitri教授的教科书
that from textbook by Professor Dimitri
对接英亩现在是一件非常有趣的事情
butts acres now a very interesting thing
我们不会全力以赴
we are not going to use the full
渐变我们只是你要使用
gradient we are only you going to use
各个组件的渐变
the gradients of individual components
是的，最小的是什么
right so what does the minimum of an
个别组件看起来很好
individual component look like well the
最小的单个组件是
minimum of an individual component is
当我们可以设置这个东西时达到
attained when we can set this thing to
零，如果你这个东西变成零
zero and that thing becomes zero if you
只需选择X等于BI除以AI
just pick X equal to B I divided by AI
对我们来说是一个单一的组成部分
right so a single component we can be
通过这种选择最小化，这样你就可以做到
minimized by that choice so you can do a
一点算术算术几何
little bit of arithmetic mean geometric
用它来表示不等式
mean type inequalities to draw this
图片
picture
总的来说，我从1到n就是这样
so overall I from 1 through n this is
这个比率AIbibi的最小值
the minimum value of this ratio AI bi bi
让我们说这是最大值
and let's say this is the max value of
AIbibi，我们知道封闭形式
AI bi bi and we know that closed-form
解决方案是真正的解决方案
solution that is the true solution so
你可以用一些代数来验证
you can verify with some algebra that
该解决方案将位于此间隔期内
that solution will lie in this interval
所以，让我们你可能想要这样
so let's so you you may want to this is
一些微小的运动对你有希望
a tiny exercise for you hopefully some
你喜欢像我这样的不平等吗？
of you love inequalities like me so this
希望不是这么糟糕的运动
is hopefully not such a bad exercise but
你可以验证在这个范围内
you can verify that within this range of
个别分钟和最大值是
the individual mins and max is where the
当然，综合解决方案也是如此
combined solution lies so of course
直觉上你会有物理风格
intuitively you would have physics style
以为你会猜到这一点
thinking you would have guessed that
马上所以这意味着当你
right away so it means when you are
外面的个人解决方案
outside where the individual solutions
让我们称之为遥远的区域
let's call this the far out zone and
这边也是远方的区域
also this side is the far out zone and
这个区域内的真实
this region within which the true
最低能骗你能说好这是
minimum can lie you can say okay that's
混乱的地方为什么我要打电话
the region of confusion why I'm calling
因为那里是混乱的地区
it the region of confusion because there
通过最小化你的个人
by minimizing an individual fi you're
不能分辨出什么是
not going to be able to tell what is the
结合X星，这是所有和非常
combined X star that's all and a very
有趣的事情发生在现在
interesting thing happens now just to
获得一些数学洞察力
gain some mathematical insight into that
模拟，我告诉你，如果你
simulation that I showed you that if you
有一个超出此范围的标量X.
have a scalar X that is outside this
混淆区域，表明如果
region of confusion which states that if
你远离其中的地区
you are far from the region within which
一个最佳的谎言，所以你很远
an optimum can lie so you're far away
你刚开始进步了
you've just started out your progress
你做了一个随机初始化最
you made a random initialization most
可能离一个地方很远
likely a far away from where the
解决方案是假设你在哪里
solution is so suppose that's where you
当你在那么远的时候会发生什么
are what happens when you're in that far
如果你在那么遥远的地方那么出去
out region so if you're in that far out
区域
region
你使用一些随机梯度
you use a stochastic gradient of some
eyuth组件所以完全渐变
eyuth component so the full gradient
看起来像一个随机
will look like that a stochastic
渐变看起来像这个组件
gradient looks like this one component
当你远在外面时
and when you are far out outside that
最小和最大政权然后你可以检查
min and Max regime then you can check by
只是看着它
just by just looking at it that a
在遥远的随机梯度
stochastic gradient in the far away
制度具有完全相同的符号
regime has exactly the same sign as the
完全渐变
full gradient
它说的是什么梯度下降
what does gradient descent do it says
好好走向的方向
well walk in the direction of the
负梯度，如果远离
negative gradient and if far away from
的区域外的最佳
the optimum outside the region of
混淆你的随机梯度
confusion your stochastic gradient has
与真实梯度相同的符号可能
the same sign as the true gradient may
它是以更线性的代数术语
be in more linear algebra terms it makes
你知道它与之形成一个锐角
you know it makes an acute angle with
你的渐变意味着即使
your gradient that means if even though
随机梯度并不完全是
a stochastic gradient is not exactly the
完全渐变它有一些组件
full gradient it has some component in
这个真正的梯度的方向
the direction of the true gradient this
在这里是1d它是完全相同的标志
is 1d here it is exactly the same sign
在多个方面，这是一个想法
in multiple dimensions this is the idea
它将有一些组件
that it will have some component in the
当真正的梯度方向
direction of the true gradient when
你很远，这意味着如果你那么
you're far away which means if you then
使用该方向进行更新
use that direction to make an update in
那种风​​格你最终会变得坚实
that style you will end up making solid
进步和美丽是在时间
progress and the beauty is in the time
它本来会让你做一个单一的
it would have taken you to do one single
批梯度下降迭代远
iteration of batch gradient descent far
你可以做百万随机步骤
away you can do million stochastic steps
每一步都会取得一些进展
and each step will make some progress
这就是为什么我们看到这种戏剧性的原因
and that's why you we see this dramatic
这是第一种情况
initial again this is in the 1d case
这在数学上是明确的
this is explicit mathematically in the
高D情况这是更直观的确定
high D case this is more intuitive ok
没有关于角度的进一步假设
without further assumptions about angles
等人无法做出如此广泛的主张
etc one can't make such a broad claim
但直觉上这就是正在发生的事情
but intuitively this is what's happening
为什么你看到这个令人敬畏的初始
on why you see this awesome initial
速度
speed
一旦你进入了该地区
and once you inside the region of
混乱然后这种行为破裂了
confusion then this behavior breaks down
我们有一些随机梯度
some stochastic gradient we have the
一些可能与完全梯度相同的符号
same sign as the full gradient some may
不，这就是为什么你可以疯了
not and that's why you can get at crazy
因此这个简单的1d例子
fluctuations so this simple 1d example
那种确切地告诉你我们看到了什么
kind of exactly shows you what we saw in
那张照片和人们真的很喜欢
that picture and people really loved
这个初步进展因为我们经常
this initial progress because often we
也做早点停止你知道火车
also do early stopping you know train
一段时间然后你说好的我
for some time and then you say ok I'm
如果你纯粹是一个人那么重要的话
done so importantly if you are purely an
优化人没有这么想
optimization person not thinking so much
请在机器学习方面
in terms of machine learning when please
请记住，随机梯度
keep in mind that stochastic gradient
下降或随机梯度法是
descent or stochastic gradient method is
没有这么好的优化方法
not such a great optimization method
因为曾经在混乱的地区
because once in the region of confusion
它可以永远地波动
it can just fluctuate all over forever
在机器学习中你说哦
and in machine learning you say oh the
混乱的地方，这很好
region of confusion that's fine it'll
让我的方法健壮，让我的
make my method robust gonna make my
神经网络训练更强大的意志
neural network training more robust will
我们更广泛地概括了等等
generalize better etcetera etcetera we
这样那取决于哪个框架
like that so it depends on which frame
你好，所以就是这样
of mind you are in ok so that's that's
关于随机性的令人敬畏的事情
the awesome thing about the stochastic
渐变法所以我现在就给你了
gradient method so I'll give you now the
关键数学思想背后的
key mathematical ideas behind the
SGD的成功就像这一点
success of SGD this was like little
插图非常抽象地这是一个
illustration very abstractly this is an
整个机器记录的想法
idea that records throughout machine
学习和整个理论
learning and throughout theoretical
计算机科学和统计学随时都有
computer science and statistics any time
你需要计算一个
you're faced with the need to compute an
昂贵的数量诉诸于
expensive quantity resort to
随机化加快了
randomization to speed up the
计算SGD就是一个例子
computation SGD is one example the true
渐变是很昂贵的计算，所以我们
gradient was expensive to compute so we
创建一个真实的随机估计
create a randomized estimate of the true
梯度和随机估计是
gradient and the randomized estimate is
更快的计算和
much faster to compute and
数学上会发生什么
mathematically what will start happening
是
is
这取决于如何好您的随机
depending on how good your randomized
估计是你的方法可能会也可能不会
estimate is your method may or may not
收敛到你正确的答案
converge to the right answer so you of
当然，人们必须要小心什么
course one has to be careful about what
一个人做出的特别随机估计
particular randomized estimate one makes
所以，即使我真的很抽象
so but really abstractly even if I
没有向你展示这个想法的主意
hadn't shown you the main idea this idea
你可以申请许多其他设置，如果
you can apply in many other settings if
你有一个困难的数量出现
you have a difficult quantity come up
随机估计并保存
with a randomized estimate and save on
计算这是非常重要的
computation this is a very important
整个机器学习的主题
theme throughout machine learning and
数据科学没关系，这是关键
data science okay and this is the key
财产如此随机的梯度下降
property so stochastic gradient descent
它使用随机梯度随机
it uses stochastic gradients stochastic
在这里你只是非常松散地使用你知道
is here just used very loosely you know
它只是意味着有一些随机化
it just means there's some randomization
这就是它的意思
that's all it means
而属性是关键属性
and the property the key property that
我们有期待的
we have is in expectation the
期望结束了
expectation is over
无论你使用什么随机性，如果你
whatever randomness you used so if you
选择你知道一些随机训练
picked you know some random training
数据指出了百万那么
data point out of the million then it is
期望超过概率
the expectation is over the probability
分配什么样的
distribution over what kind of
如果你喜欢挑选你使用的随机性
randomness you used if you like picked
从一百万随机统一
uniformly at random from a million
然后这个期望结束了
points then this expectation is over
那个统一的概率但关键
that uniform probability but the key
SGD或至少版本的财产
property for SGD or at least the version
我正在谈论的新元是在
of SGD i am talking about is that in
对随机性的期望
expectation over that randomness the
你假装使用的东西
thing that you are pretending to use
而不是真正的梯度
instead of the true gradient in
期待实际上是真的
expectation actually it is the true
渐变所以在统计语言这个
gradient so in statistics language this
被称为随机梯度
is called the stochastic gradient that
我们用的是的无偏估计
we use is an unbiased estimate of the
真正的渐变，这是一个非常
true gradient and this is a very
数学中的重要属性
important property in the mathematical
随机梯度下降分析
analysis of stochastic gradient descent
这是一个无偏见的估计和
that it is an unbiased estimate and
任何时候你都可以直观地说出来
intuitively speaking anytime you did any
在课堂上或书中或讲座中的证明
proof in class or in the book or lecture
注意你在哪里使用true
notes wherever where you were using true
渐变或多或少你可以做到这些
gradients more or less you can do those
相同的证据更多
same proofs more
少并不总是使用随机
less not always using stochastic
通过封装替换渐变
gradients by replace by encapsulating
一切都在期待中
everything within expectations over the
随机性我会告诉你一个例子
randomness I'll show you an example of
我的意思是我只是想做什么
what I mean by that I'm just trying to
为您简化，特别是
simplify that for you and in particular
unbiasness是伟大的，所以它意味着我
the unbiasness is great so it means I
可以插入这些随机的
can kind of plug in these stochastic
渐变代替真正的渐变
gradients in place of the true gradient
而且我还在做一些有意义的事情
and I'm still doing something meaningful
所以这是早些时候回答的问题
so this is answering that earlier
问你知道为什么这个随机的东西
question you know why this random stuff
为什么我们认为它可能会起作用但是
why it should we think it may work but
还有另一个非常重要的方面
there's another very important aspect to
它为什么它超出了unbiasness
it why it works beyond this unbiasness
那噪音的数量还是喜欢的
that the amount of noise or like the
随机性的量的量是
amount of amount of stochasticity is
控制所以只是因为它是一个
controlled so just because it is an
无偏估计并不意味着它
unbiased estimate doesn't mean that it's
为了这个原因，为什么要这样做呢
going to work that well why because it
可能仍然非常波动
could still fluctuate hugely right
在这里减去无穷大
essentially plus infinity here minus
无限这里你取一个平均值你
infinity here you take an average you
得到零，这基本上是无偏见的
get zero so that is essentially unbiased
但波动是巨大的
but the fluctuation is gigantic
所以每当谈论估计时
so whenever talking about estimates
什么是我们需要的其他关键数量
what's the other key quantity we need to
关心超出预期
care about beyond expectation
在通关和真正关键的事情
in clearance and really the key thing
它决定了速度
that governs the speed at which
随机梯度下降完成工作
stochastic gradient descent does the job
我们希望它做的是多少
that we want it to do is how much
随机梯度有变化
variance do the stochastic gradient have
只是这个简单的统计点
just this simple statistical point in
事实是一系列的核心
fact is at the heart of a sequence of
过去五年的研究进展
research progress in the past five years
在随机梯度领域
in the field of stochastic gradient
人们真的努力
where people have worked really hard to
拿出新的和更新的票友和
come up with newer and newer fancier and
随机梯度的发烧友版本
fancier versions of stochastic gradient
哪个有unbiasness属性但是
which have the unbiasness property but
有越来越小的变种和
have smaller and smaller variants and
你拥有的方差越小
the smaller the variance you have the
你的随机梯度更好
better your stochastic gradient is as a
替换真正的梯度和
replacement of the true gradient and of
当然更好的是更换
course the better is the replacement of
真正的渐变然后你真正得到
the true gradient then you truly get
你知道n加速好吧
that you know n time speed-up okay so
收敛的速度取决于如何
the speed of convergence depends on how
嘈杂的随机梯度是它
noisy the stochastic gradients are it
好像我走得太慢我不会
seems like I'm going too slow I won't be
能够做一个证明我如果它吮吸，但
able to do a proof i if it sucks but
我只是让我告诉你
I'll but let's let me actually tell you
然后是关于而不是证据
then about rather than the the proof
我想我会和Gil分享这个证据
I think I'll share the proof with Gil
因为我想要的证明
because the proof that I want to want
你实际上告诉你说话给了一个
you to actually show you talk gives a
随机梯度的证明是
proof of stochastic gradient is
凸起和非凸起都表现良好
well-behaved on both convex and non
凸问题和我想要的证明
convex problems and the proof I wanted
显示是非凸的情况
to show was for the non convex case
因为它适用于神经网络
because it applies to neural networks so
你可能对这个证据感到好奇
you may be curious about that proof and
显而易见，证明更简单
remarkably that proof is much simpler
比凸问题的情况所以让
than the case of convex problems so let
我只提一些非常重要的
me just mention some very important
关于随机梯度的点是如此均匀
points about stochastic gradient so even
虽然这种方法一直存在
though this method has been around since
1951年每个深度学习工具包都有它
1951 every deep learning toolkit has it
我们在课堂上学习它有
and we are studying it in class there
我们能说什么之间仍然存在差距
are still gaps between what we can say
从理论上讲，会发生什么
theoretically and what happens in
练习，我会告诉你那些差距
practice and I'll show you those gaps
已经鼓励你去思考
already and encourage you to think about
如果你愿意的话
those if you wish
让我们回顾一下我们的问题，
so let's look back at our problem and
告诉你两个变种，所以这里是
tell you about two variants so here are
这两个变种我会问，如果有的话
the two variants I'm going to ask if any
你熟悉这个变种
of you is familiar with this variant
以某种方式或其他方式让我只是
in some way or the other so let's I just
称之为可行，这里没有
call it feasible here there are no
约束所以我从任何随机开始
constraints so I start with any random
在深层网络中选择的矢量
vector of your choice in deep network
训练你必须更努力地工作
training you have to work harder and
那么这就是你正确运行的迭代
then this is the iteration you run right
选项一和选项二所以选项一
option one and option two so option one
说这是我们在课堂上的想法
says that was the idea we had in class
随机挑选一些训练数据点
randomly pick some training data point
用它随机梯度做什么呢
use it stochastic gradient well what do
我们的意思是随便挑选你的那一刻
we mean by randomly pick the moment you
使用你必须定义的随机词
use the word random you have to define
什么是随机性，所以一个随机性
what's the randomness so one randomness
是我们训练的统一概率
is uniform probability of our n training
数据点是一个随机性的
data points that is one randomness the
其他版本是你选择培训
other version is you pick a training
没有替换的数据点所以我这样
data point without replacement so I so
有替换意味着你只知道
with replacement means you know just
每次画画时都是随机的
uniformly at random each time you draw a
从1到n的数字使用那个
number from one through n use that
随机梯度移动就意味着
stochastic gradient move on which means
同样的观点很容易被选中
the same point can easily be picked
两次也没有更换手段
twice also and without replacement means
如果你选择了第三点
if you've picked a point number three
你不会再去挑选它
you're not going to pick it again until
你经历了整个训练
you've gone through the entire training
数据集有两种类型
data set those are two types of
随机性你会使用哪个版本
randomness which version would you use
没有正确或错误的答案
there is no right or wrong answer to
这个我只是采取了民意调查会是什么
this I'm just taking a poll what would
你使用认为你正在写一个
you use think that you're writing a
为此计划，也许真的想
program for this and maybe think really
实际上实际上是这样的
pragmatically practically so that's
足够暗示哪个版本会
enough of an hint which version would
你使用我只是好奇谁会使用
you use I'm just curious who would use
一请举手谁和谁
one please raise hands who and the the
排除他们改革的赞美我
exclusion the compliment they reform I
不知道也许有些人
don't know maybe some people are
尚未决定谁会使用两个极少数
undecided who would use two very few
人还好你们有多少人使用神经
people okay how many of you use neural
网络培训工具包就好
network training tool kits like
tensorflowpi火炬whatnot哪个
tensorflow pi torch whatnot which
他们正在使用的版本
version are they using
实际上是现实世界中的每个人
actually every person in the real world
正在使用版本2你真的会
is using version 2 are you really gonna
每次随机浏览你的RAAM
randomly go through your RAAM each time
选择随机点，他们会杀了你的
to pick random points they'll kill your
GPU表现就像什么
GPU performance like anything what
人们做的是拿一个数据集使用前
people do is take a data set use a pre
随机操作然后只是Boop
shuffle operation and then just Boop
通过数据流什么的
stream through the data what the
流经数据意味着没有
streaming through the data mean without
实际上替换所有工具包
replacement so all the toolkits actually
正在使用无替代品
are using the without replacement
版本即使直观的租金
version even though intuitively the rent
只是均匀随机感觉好得多和
just uniform random feels much nicer and
那种感觉并非毫无根据，因为
that feeling is not ill-founded because
这是我们知道的唯一版本
that's the only version we know how to
以数学方式进行分析，即便如此
analyze mathematically so even for this
方法大家研究它们
method everybody studies it their
关于它的版本是百万篇论文
million papers on it the version that is
在实践中使用的不是我们的版本
used in practice is not the version we
知道如何分析它是一个重要的开放
know how to analyze it's a major open
随机领域的问题
problem in the field of stochastic
渐变来实际分析版本
gradient to actually analyze the version
我们在实践中使用它是那种
that we use in practice it's kind of
令人尴尬，但没有
embarrassing but it's without
替换意味着非iid概率
replacement means non iid probability
理论和非iid概率论是
theory and non iid probability theory is
不那么容易
not so easy
那个答案还可以，另一个
that's the answer okay so the other
版本是这个迷你批量的想法
version is this mini batch idea which
你真的提到早期是
you mentioned really early on is that
而不是选择一个随机点我会
rather than pick one random point I'll
选一个小批量，所以我有一百万
pick a mini batch so I had a million
每次指出而不是挑选一个
points each time instead of picking one
也许我会选择10或100或者千或者
maybe I'll pick 10 or 100 or thousand or
你有什么
what have you
所以这可以平均事物的平均值
so this averages things averaging things
减少方差所以这实际上是这样
reduces the variance so this is actually
一件好事，因为数量越多
a good thing because the more quantities
你平均噪音越小
you averaged the less noise you have
这就是发生的事情
that's kind of what happens in
概率正确，所以我们挑选一个迷你
probability right so we pick a mini
批量和随机估计现在是
batch and the stochastic estimate now is
这一点，你知道不只是一个单一的梯度
this you know not just a single gradient
但平均超过一个迷你一批这样的迷你
but averaged over a mini batch so mini
一批大小的是纯香草
batch of size one is the pure vanilla
SGDmini批量大小n没什么
SGD mini batch of size n is nothing
除了纯粹的梯度下降
other than pure gradient descent
介于两者之间的是什么人
something in between is what people
实际使用
actually use
而且只是理论分析
and again the theoretical analysis only
如果选择小批量，则存在
exists if the mini-batch is picked with
更换不是没有替换所以
replacement not without replacement so
其中一个原因实际上是非常的
one of the reasons actually a very
在理论上你不会获得重要的东西
important thing in theory you don't gain
在计算收益方面太多了
too much in terms of computational gains
利用mini实现收敛速度
on convergence speed by using mini
比赛，但迷你批次真的
matches but mini batches are really
至关重要，特别是你知道深刻
crucial especially in you know deep
因为他们学习GPU风格的训练
learning GPU style training because they
允许你每个人并行做事
allow you to do things in parallel each
线程或每个核心或子核心或小
thread or each core or sub core or small
芯片或你有什么依赖你
chip or what-have-you depending on your
硬件可以与一个
hardware can be working with one
随机梯度所以迷你批次是
stochastic gradient so mini batch is the
迷你批次越大越多
larger the mini batch the more things
你可以并行做这么小的批次
you can do in parallel so mini batches
被人们极大地利用来给予
are greatly exploited by people to give
你是一个廉价的并行版本
you a cheap version of parallelism and
并行性发生在哪里
where does the parallelism happen you
可以认为每个核心计算一个
can think that each core computes a
随机梯度所以困难的部分是
stochastic gradient so the hard part is
没有添加这些东西和制作
not adding these things up and making
更新到X的难点是
the update to X the hard part is
计算随机梯度，如果
computing a stochastic gradient so if
你可以计算那些10000
you can compute 10,000 of those in
并行，因为你有10,000个核心
parallel because you have 10,000 cores
非常适合你，这就是原因
great for you and that's the reason
人们喜欢使用小型批次但是
people love using mini batches but a
好的一面在这里说这也是这个
nice side remark here this is also this
让我们接近研究边缘
brings us close to the research edge of
事情再次证明以及你爱用
things again that well you'd love to use
非常大的迷你批次，所以你可以
very large mini batches so that you can
完全最大化并行性
fully max out on the parallelism
对你有用，也许你有一个
available to you right maybe you have a
多GPU系统，如果你是朋友
multi GPU system if you're friends with
NVDA或Google我只有两个GPU
NVDA or Google I only have like two GPUs
但这取决于你有多少GPU
but it depends on how many GPUs you have
你真的想要最大化
you'd like to really max out on
并行性使你真的可以
parallelism so that you can really
紧紧抓住大数据集
crunch through big datasets as fast as
可能，但你知道会发生什么
possible but you know what happens with
非常大的迷你批次，如果你有
very large mini batches so if you have
非常大的迷你批次随机
very large mini batches stochastic
渐变开始看起来更饱满
gradient starts looking more like full
梯度下降，也称为
gradient descent which is also called
批量梯度下降并不坏
batch gradient descent that's not a bad
这是真棒优化的事情
thing that's awesome for optimization
但这是一个奇怪的难题
but it is a weird conundrum that happens
在训练深度神经网络这个
in training deep neural networks this
问题类型我们不会有
type of problem we wouldn't have for
凸优化但在深度神经网络中
convex optimization but in deep neural
网络这真是令人不安的事情
networks this is really disturbing thing
碰巧，如果你使用这个非常大
happens that if you use this very large
迷你批次你的方法开始
mini-batches your method starts
类似于梯度下降的意思
resembling gradient descent that means
它会降低噪音，以便这样做
it decreases noise so much so that this
混乱的地方缩小了这么多
region of confusion shrinks so much
一切听起来不错，但最终结果
which all sounds good but it ends up
是机器学习非常糟糕
being really bad for machine learning
这就是我在机器中所说的
that's what I said that in machine
学习你想要一些地区
learning you want some region of
不确定性及其实际意义
uncertainty and what it means actually
是很多人都在工作
is a lot of people are have been working
在这包括在大公司那
on this including at big companies that
如果你减少那个不确定的区域
if you reduce that region of uncertainty
太多你最终过度拟合你的
too much you end up overfitting your
神经网络，然后它开始
neural network and then it starts
吮吸其测试数据看不见的数据
sucking in its test data unseen data
性能所以尽管如此
performance so even though for
并行编程优化
parallelism programming optimization
理论大小批量很棒
Theory big mini-batch is awesome
不幸的是要付出代价
unfortunately there's price to be paid
它会伤害你的测试错误性能
it hurts your test error performance and
有方法的人的种种都
there all sorts of methods people are
试图做饭，包括萎缩
trying to cook up including shrinking
数据相应或改变神经
data accordingly or changing neural
网络架构和各种各样的
network architecture and all sorts of
你可以提出想法的想法
ideas you can cook up your ideas for
你最喜欢的建筑如何制作
your favorite architecture how to make a
大型迷你批次没有伤害
large mini batch without hurting the
最后的表现，但它仍然
final performance but it's still
关于如何做一些公开的问题
somewhat of an open question on how to
最佳选择哪个更大
optimally select which many larger
小批量即使如此应该如此
mini-batch so should be so even though
你看到这些想法很简单
these ideas are simple you see that
每一个简单的想法都会导致整个潜艇
every simple idea leads to an entire sub
SGD的面积所以这里很实用
area of SGD so here are practical
人们有各种挑战
challenges people have various
解决这些挑战的启发式方法
heuristics for solving these challenges
你可以自己做饭，但事实并非如此
you can cook up your own but it's not
一个想法总是有效，如果你
that one idea always works so if you
看看SGD有什么动作部件
look at SGD what are the moving parts
SGD中的运动部件是渐变的
the moving parts in SGD the gradients
随机梯度步长
stochastic gradients the step size the
小批量如此
mini batch so
我应该如何选择步长
how should I pick step sizes very
不平凡的问题不同深刻
non-trivial problem different deep
学习工具包可能有所不同
learning toolkits may have different
调整自动化的方法，但它是
ways of automating that tuning but it's
其中一件令人痛苦的事情
one of the painful things which
小批量使用更换
mini-batch to use with replacement
没有替换我已经告诉你了
without replacement I already showed you
但我应该如何使用哪个迷你批次
but which mini-batch should I use how
大，这应该是一件容易的事
large that should be again not an easy
问题来回答如何计算
question to answer how to compute
任何人都知道随机梯度
stochastic gradients does anybody know
如何计算随机梯度
how stochastic gradients are computed
深入网络培训任何人都知道
for deep Network training anybody know
有一个非常着名的算法叫做
there is a very famous algorithm called
反向传播，即反向传播
back propagation that back propagation
算法用于计算单个
algorithm is used to compute a single
随机梯度有些人使用
stochastic gradient some people use the
单词支持意味着SGD但是回来了
word back prop to mean SGD but what back
道具真正的意思是一些某种
prop really means is some some kind of
计算你的算法a
algorithm which computes for you a
单随机梯度，因此你
single stochastic gradient and hence you
知道这个tensorflow等这些工具包
know this tensorflow etc these toolkits
他们提出了各种各样的方法
they come up with all sorts of ways to
自动计算梯度
automate the computation of a gradient
因为这真的是主要的事情
because really that's the main thing and
然后其他想法，如渐变剪辑
then other ideas like gradient clipping
和动量等有一堆
and momentum etc there's a bunch of
其他想法和理论
other ideas and the theoretical
我刚才提到的挑战
challenges I mentioned to you already
证明它实际上是有效的
proving that it works that it actually
解决了它打算做的事情
solves what it set out to do
不幸的是我太慢了我做不到
unfortunately I was too slow I couldn't
向您展示令人敬畏的五行证明
show you the awesome five line proof
我认为SGD适用于神经系统
that I have that SGD works for neural
我的网络和理论分析
networks and theoretical analysis as I
说真的落后我也证明
said it's really lagging my proof also
使用替换和
uses the with replacement and the
没有替换版本的
without replacement version which is the
一个实际实现的那个
one that is actually implemented there's
在那方面进展甚微
very little progress on that there is
一些进展有一堆文件
some progress there's a bunch of papers
包括我们麻省理工学院的同事，但是
including from our colleagues at MIT but
它是相当未解决的，也是最大的
it's quite unsolved and the biggest
大多数人都在问的问题
question which most of the people in
机器学习目前很兴奋
machine learning are currently excited
关于这些日子就像是为什么
about these days is stuff like why does
SGD工作这么好神经网络，我们
SGD work so well for neural networks we
使用这种糟糕的优化方法吧
use this crappy optimization method it
一些拟合数据非常迅速
very rapidly does some fitting data is
大型神经网络很大
large neural network is large
然后这个神经网络结束了
and then this neural network ends up
具有很好的分类性能
having great classification performance
为什么会发生这种情况
why is that happening
它被称为试图解释构建一个
it's called trying to explain build a
泛化理论为什么会这样
theory of generalization why does this
一个SGD列车神经网络工作得更好
an SGD train neural network work better
比神经网络训练更多
than neural networks train with more
花哨的优化方法是一个
fancy optimization methods it's a
神秘和最谁走的人
mystery and most of the people who take
对理论机器学习的兴趣
interest in theoretical machine learning
和统计数据之一
and statistics that is one of the
他们试图理解的谜团
mysteries they are trying to understand
所以我认为这是我的SGD和
so I think that's my story of SGD and
这是我们跳过的部分，但没关系
this is the part we skip but it's ok the
SGD背后的直觉更多
the intuition behind SGD is much more
important than this so I think exactly
比这更重要，所以我认为
是的，我认为他们会很棒
yeah I think so that they'll be great